A Guide to the Papers of Maud Carter Clement, 1756-1968
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series V: Correspondence-General
  - Wyatt C. Hendrick to Maud C. Clement, January 1954, TLS. (Box-folder 16:49)
  - Katherine Fitzgerald to Maud C. Clement, April 27, 1954, ALS. (Box-folder 16:50)
  - Clifford Dowdey to Maud C. Clement, March 31, 1954, TLS. (Box-folder 16:51)
  - John Powell to Maud C. Clement, August 16, 1954, ALS. (Box-folder 16:52)
  - Reverend J. R. McAllister to Maud C. Clement, October 22, 1954 (Box-folder 16:53)
  - Louise Van H. Ingersoll to Maud C. Clement, October 1954, 2 ALS. (Box-folder 16:54)
  - Elizabeth T. White to Maud C. Clement, January 19, 1955, ALS. (Box-folder 16:55)
  - Forrest Smith to Maud C. Clement, June 4, 1955, TLS. (Box-folder 16:56)
  - Marie F. Lewis to Maud C. Clement, October 5, 1955, ALS. (Box-folder 16:57)
  - Gladys F. Winston to Maud C. Clement, October 24, 1955, ALS. (Box-folder 16:58)
  - Leslie Carter to Maud C. Clement, October 1955, 2 ALS. (Box-folder 16:59)
  - Reverend J. Rowan McAllister to Maud C. Clement, January 10, 1956, TLS. (Box-folder 16:60)
  - Elizabeth T. White to Maud C. Clement, January 13, 1956, ALS. (Box-folder 16:61)
  - Wyatt C. Hendrick to Maud C. Clement, January 13, 1956, TLS. (Box-folder 16:62)
  - Elise Todd to Maud C. Clement, March 5, 1956, ALS. (Box-folder 16:63)
  - Harry R. Elmore to Maud C. Clement, May 12, 1956, TLS. (Box-folder 16:64)
  - Marie MacGee to Maud C. Clement, May 12, 1956, ALS. (Box-folder 16:65)
  - Randolph W. Church to Maud C. Clement, May 17, 1956, TPCS (Box-folder 16:66)
  - Kim Martin to Maud C. Clement, June 19, 1956, ALS. (Box-folder 16:67)
  - Evelyn L. White to Maud C. Clement, June 20, 1956, ALS. (Box-folder 16:68)
  - Ellie Silliman to Maud C. Clement, June 20, 1956, ALS. (Box-folder 16:69)
  - George P. Gunn to Maud C. Clement, January 14, 1957, TLS. (Box-folder 16:70)
  - Beverly Dickinson to Maud C. Clement, July 17, 1957, ALS. (Box-folder 16:71)
  - Wyatt C. Hendrick to Maud C. Clement, August 29, 1957, TLS. (Box-folder 16:72)
  - Anna Kenney to Maud C. Clement, September 25, 1957, ALS. (Box-folder 16:73)
  - Elizabeth T. White to Maud C. Clement, November 10, 1957, ALS. (Box-folder 16:74)
  - E. Neil Raymond to Maud C. Clement, December 18, 1957, TLS. (Box-folder 16:75)
  - Elizabeth T. White to Maud C. Clement, January 11, 1958, ALS. (Box-folder 16:76)
  - Hodding Carter to Maud C. Clement, February 17, 1958, ALS. (Box-folder 16:77)
  - Bishop Beverly Tucker to Maud C. Clement, November 14, 1958, Letter, 2 items. (Box-folder 16:78)
  - Wyatt C. Hendrick to Maud C. Clement, 1958, 2 TLS. (Box-folder 16:79)
  - Alfred Percy to Maud C. Clement, 1958, TLS. (Box-folder 16:80)
  - Elizabeth T. White to Maud C. Clement, January 15, 1959, ALS. (Box-folder 16:81)
  - Homie Stone Carter to Maud C. Clement, March 14, 1959, ALS. (Box-folder 16:82)
  - Elizabeth T. White to Maud C. Clement, April 16, 1959, ALS. (Box-folder 16:83)
  - Henry P. Carter to Maud C. Clement, July 3, 1959, TLS. (Box-folder 16:84)
  - D. C. Loving to Maud C. Clement, July 15, 1959, TLS. (Box-folder 16:85)
  - Samuel E. Morrison to Maud C. Clement, August 17, 1959, Postcard. (Box-folder 16:86)
  - Betsy Kenny O'Brien to Maud C. Clement, August 24, 1959, ALS. (Box-folder 16:87)
  - Mrs. Douglass M. Low, Sr. to Maud C. Clement, September 17, 1959, ALS. (Box-folder 16:88)
  - Curtis Bishop to Maud C. Clement, December 9, 1959, TLS. (Box-folder 16:89)
    Bishop was president of Averett College.
  - Alfred Percy to Maud C. Clement, 1959, 3 TLS. (Box-folder 16:90)
  - Mae Crumply to Maud C. Clement, May 2, 1960, ALS. (Box-folder 16:91)
  - Sarah Carr to Maud C. Clement, May 11, 1960, ALS. (Box-folder 16:92)
  - Mrs. Robert Bachman to Maud C. Clement, May 13, 1961, ALS. (Box-folder 16:93)
  - G. V. Garrett to Maud C. Clement, December 28, 1961, TLS. (Box-folder 16:94)
  - Wirt A. Christian to Maud C. Clement, June 12, 1962, TLS. (Box-folder 16:95)
  - G. V. Garrett to Maud C. Clement, 1962, 2 TLS. (Box-folder 16:96)
  - Catherine Overbey to Maud C. Clement, April 16, 1965, ALS. (Box-folder 16:97)
  - Weld S. Carter to Maud C. Clement, January 18, 1968, TLS. (Box-folder 16:98)
  - Elizabeth T. White to Maud C. Clement, n.d., ALS (fragment). (Box-folder 16:99)
  - Mr. Bryant to Maud C. Clement, May 4, Envelope. (Box-folder 16:100)
  - 3 miscellaneous items, n.d. (Box-folder 16:101)
- Series VI: Correspondence re: Maud C. Clement Publications
  - re: The History of Pittsylvania County, Virginia by Maud C. Clement, 1929-1955, 25 items. (Box-folder 17:1)
  - re: The History of The Garden Club of Virginia by Maud C. Clement, 1931, 2 ALS. (Box-folder 17:2)
  - Re:In Memoriam: The Reverend Chiswell Dabney by Maud C. Clement, 1954, 12 items. (Box-folder 17:3)
  - Re:Lanier, Her Name by Maud C. Clement, 1956-1960, 19 items. (Box-folder 17:4)
  - Re:The History of The 29th Division,1956, 2 ALS. (Box-folder 17:5)
  - Re:The Early Homes of Chatham by Maud C. Clement, 1957, 8 items. (Box-folder 17:6)
  - Re: The Turn of the Wheel by Maud C. Clement, 1958-1961, 10 items. (Box-folder 17:7)
  - Re: The Recollections of the Confederte Veterans of Pittsylvania County, Virginia, 1861-1865 by Maud C. Clement, ca. 1961-1962, 5 items. (Box-folder 17:7)
  - Re: The Washington Iron Works by Maud C. Clement, January 22, 1962, TLS. (AMS in box 18) (Box-folder 17:8)
  - Newspaper clipping re: Frontiers Along The Upper Roanoke River, 1740-1776 by Maud C. Clement, n.d., Newspaper clipping. (Box-folder 17:9)
- Series VII: Manuscripts of Articles
  - Thomas Carter II of Buford, Lancaster County, Virginia by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 52 pp. (Box-folder 18:1)
  - Ancestry of Rachel Donelson Jackson, 1929, AMsS, 11 pp. (Box-folder 18:2)
  - Rachel Jackson: Beloved Wife of President Andrew Jackson by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 25 pp. (Box-folder 18:3)
  - The Life of A Colonial Child in Pittsylvania, Virginia, 1767-1779 by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 11 pp. (Box-folder 18:4)
  - Notes on Rachel Donelson Jackson,n.d., AMsS, 10 pp. (Box-folder 18:5)
  - The Childhood of Rachel Donelson: Wife of President Andrew Jackson by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 6 pp. (Box-folder 18:6)
  - Easter Message, n.d., 3 ms. (Box-folder 18:7)
  - Hall of Fame of Rawley Martin Chapter United Daughters of the Confederacy by Maud C. Clement, October 7, 1962, TMsS, 3 pp. (Box-folder 18:8)
  - Copy of Muster Roll of Co. I, 53rd Va. Regiment from Pittsylvania Courthouse (compiled from memory), n.d., ca. 28 pp. (Box-folder 18:9)
  - Notes and Thoughts on Virginia, The South and Related Subjects by Maud C. Clement, n.d., Ms, 37 pp. (Box-folder 18:10)
  - Poems by Maud C. Clement, 1958, 3 ms, 18 pp. (Box-folder 18:11)
  - The Price of Freedom by Maud C. Clement, n.d., 2 ms, 32 pp. (Box-folder 18:12)
  - Revolutionary Hospitality in the Dan Valley by Maud C. Clement, ca. 1943, AMsS. (Box-folder 18:13)
  - Saint Patrick by Maud C. Clement, March 17, 1960, 2 AMsS, 16 pp. (Box-folder 18:14)
  - Some Virginia Gentlemen and Their Homes by Maud C. Clement, n. d., 3 ms, 140 pp. (Box-folder 18:15)
  - The Washington Iron Works by Maud C. Clement, n.d., 2 AMsS, ca. 20 pp. (Box-folder 18:16)
    Cover letter January 22, 1962.
  - Your Heritage of Valor by Maud C. Clement, September 11, 1958, AMsS, 10 pp. (Box-folder 18:17)
  - Illustrations for Turn of The Wheel by Maud C. Clement n.d., 4 items. (Box-folder 18:18)
  - Donelson Pictures, n.d., 8 items. (Box-folder 18:19)
  - War Recollections of The Confederate Veterans of Pittsylvania County: 1861-1865 by Maud C. Clement, n.d., 84 pp. (Box-folder 18:20)
- Series VIII: Garden Club Speeches
  - Plant Materials at Seed Bed by Maud C. Clement, March 5, 1926, AMsS, 9 pp. (Box-folder 19:1)
  - The Iris by Maud C. Clement, 1930, TMs, 16 pp. (Box-folder 19:2)
  - Outline of Address made at Reidsville, N.C. by Maud C. Clement, April 13, 1932, AMsS. (Box-folder 19:3)
  - Life Along Dan River by Maud C. Clement, 1932, AMsS, 2 pp. (Box-folder 19:4)
  - The Adventure of Garden Making, May 26, 1933, AMsS, 2 pp. (Box-folder 19:5)
  - Gardener's talk before teachers of Danville, October 1933, AMsS. (Box-folder 19:6)
  - Perennials- Our Flower Friends, November 1, 1935, 2 AMsS, 14 pp. (Box-folder 19:7)
  - Re: The Iris, 1935, 25 items, 36 pp. (Box-folder 19:8)
  - Autumn in the Garden, 1935, AMsS, 13 pp. (Box-folder 19:9)
  - Farming As A Way of Life, n.d. [1938?], AMsS, 14 pp. (Box-folder 19:10)
  - The South- The Nation's Number One Economic Problem, As Viewed from Henry County, Virginia by Maud C. Clement, May 1939, 2 AMsS, 28 pp. (Box-folder 19:11)
  - The Adventure of Making A Virginia Garden, May 3, 1940, AMsS, 3 pp. (Box-folder 19:12)
  - Wild Flowers by Maud C. Clement, May 1940, AMsS, 20 pp. (Box-folder 19:13)
  - On this Foundation- Latin America by Dr. Stanley Rycroft: Review by Maud C. Clement, April 12, 1943, AMsS, 11 pp. (Box-folder 19:14)
  - Re:Garden Gossip,1951-1952, 23 items, 31 pp. (Box-folder 19:15)
  - Historic Homes and Gardens of Chatham by Maud C. Clement, 1963, AMsS, 32 pp. (Box-folder 19:16)
  - All About Flowers in General by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 6 pp. (Box-folder 19:17)
  - Color in the Garden by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 3 pp. (Box-folder 19:18)
  - Old Pittsylvania Gardens by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 21 pp. (Box-folder 19:19)
  - Thoughts on Boxwood by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 3 pp. (Box-folder 19:20)
  - Shakespeare in Chatham Hall Gardens by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 20 pp. (Box-folder 19:21)
  - Maud Clement Garden Club agenda, 1960-1964, 3 items. (Box-folder 19:22)
- Series IX: Church History and Religious Writings
  - The Antiquity of the Liturgy of Holy Communion by Maud C. Clement, n.d., 4 ms, 35 pp. (Box-folder 20:1)
  - The Bible and History by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS, 2 pp. (Box-folder 20:2)
  - The Christian Church through the Ages by Maud C. Clement, n.d., 2 ms, 32 pp. (Box-folder 20:3)
  - Church of The Disciple in Pittsylvania County by Maud C. Clement, n.d., AMsS. (Box-folder 20:4)
  - The Church in A World At War by Maud C. Clement, 1942 February 4, 2 AMsS, 8 pp. (Box-folder 20:5)
  - Chart- Epitome of The History of The Holy Catholic Church,1946, 3 items. (Box-folder 20:6)
  - The First Century of Christianity, n. d., 2 AMsS, 21 pp. (Box-folder 20:7)
  - Outline for Highlights of Church History,n. d., AMsS, 8 pp. (Box-folder 20:8)
  - Holy Things-Holy Place, by Maud C. Clement, n. d., AMsS, 4 pp. (Box-folder 20:9)
  - How the Gospel of Jesus Came to Me, n.d., AMsS, 23 pp. (Box-folder 20:10)
  - Dr. Edmund Jennings Lee: An Appreciation, n.d., AMsS, 5 pp. (Box-folder 20:11)
  - Man's Adventure- God, n.d. [1931?], AMsS, 4 pp. (Box-folder 20:12)
  - Man's Upward Climb to God, n.d., AMsS, 8 pp. (Box-folder 20:13)
  - Problems of Girlhood, 1943 October 5, AMsS, 8 pp. (Box-folder 20:14)
  - Rectors of Emmanuel Church, Chatham, Va. 1844-1959, 1959, AMsS. (Box-folder 20:15)
  - Shall We Go Forward, Stand Still, or Slip Backwards? 1930 February 4, AMsS, 5 pp. (Box-folder 20:16)
  - Spiritual Growth, 1930 April 5, AMsS, 3 pp. (Box-folder 20:17)
  - Thoughts on Abraham, n. d., AMsS, 16 pp. (Box-folder 20:18)
  - Thoughts on Various Aspects of Religion, n. d., AMsS, 16 pp. (Box-folder 20:19)
  - The Beginning of The History of Emmanuel Church... 1969, TMsS, 24 pp. (Box-folder 20:20)
  - Notes for the 125th Anniversary of Emmanuel Church, 1969, AMsS, 79 pp. (Box-folder 20:21)
  - Notes and Draft:The History of Emmanuel Church, 1969, AMsS, 86 pp. (Box-folder 20:22)
  - Notes for The History of The Church,n. d., AMsS, 20 pp. (Box-folder 20:23)
  - Emmanuel Church, Chatham, Va. 1844-1944, n. d., AMsS, 24 pp. (Box-folder 20:24)
  - Exeter Cathedral- Pictures, Notes & A Plan, 1938, Pamphlet, 14 pp. (Box-folder 20:25)
  - Emmanuel Church, Chatham, Va., Centennial, 1844-1944, 1944, 2 items, 40 pp. (Box-folder 20:26)
  - Saint Peter's Church, 1844-1944, Charlotte, N.C., 1944, 32 pp. (Box-folder 20:27)
  - A Cenutry of Service, Watson Memorial Methodist Church, 1944, 16 pp. (Box-folder 20:28)
  - Memorial Edition of The Communion Ritual, 1949, 16 pp. (Box-folder 20:29)
  - When You're United Thanks Offering Treasurer, n. d., 24 pp. (Box-folder 20:30)
  - The Church Was Already There by Henry P. Van Dusen, Saturday Evening Post, 1947 April 7, 4 pp. (Box-folder 20:31)
  - Churchmen In the News, ca. 1941-1945, Clippings, 18 items. (Box-folder 20:32)
  - A Service of Worship for Women's Groups, n. d., Pamphlet, 2 pp. (Box-folder 20:33)
- Series XIV: Local History Pittsylvania County and Southwest Virginia
  - An Act for Establishing a Town in the County of Pittsylvania, 1770, n. d., DS, typescript. (Box-folder 21:1)
  - List of Chatham men in World War II, n. d. (Box-folder 21:2)
  - Aftermath of The Civil War in Pittsylvania County and Central South Virginia by Maud C. Clement, n. d., AMsS, 4 pp. (Box-folder 21:3)
  - Some Benefactors of Chatham in Past Years, n.d., AMsS, 5 pp. (Box-folder 21:4)
  - Notes on Pittsylvania County Participants in the Civil War, n.d., AMsS, 36 pp. (Box-folder 21:5)
  - The Confederate Soldiers of Pittsylvania County, Va by Maud C. Clement, n. d., AMsS, 35 pp. (Box-folder 21:6)
  - Confederate Veterans buried in Chatham Cemetary as Listed by the U. D. C., n. d., 2 pp. (Box-folder 21:7)
  - Speech before Gretna Chamber of Commerce by Maud C. Clement, n. d., AMsS, 24 pp. (Box-folder 21:8)
  - Indians by Maud C. Clement, 1932 March 6, AMsS, 2 pp. (Box-folder 21:9)
  - Indians by Maud C. Clement, n. d., AMsS, 6 pp. (Box-folder 21:10)
  - Indians- Our Local Tribes, 1933 January, AMsS, 2 pp. (Box-folder 21:11)
  - Indians of South Piedmont, Virginia, n. d., AMsS, 9 pp. (Box-folder 21:12)
  - Indian Places in Henry County Mentioned in Land Grants, n. d., AMsS, 2 pp. (Box-folder 21:13)
  - Marriage Lists 1781-1813 (Pittsylvania County), n. d. (Box-folder 21:14)
  - Notes on the Portraits in the Chatham Court House, n. d., 5 AMsS, 22 pp. (Box-folder 21:15)
  - Land Sales in Pittsylvania County, Va, 1768-1823, n. d., 10 pp. (Box-folder 21:16)
  - List of tithables of Pittsylvania County, Va. 1776, n. d., 15 pp. (Box-folder 21:17)
  - Officers of Pittsylvania Militia- War of 1812, n. d., 8 pp. (Box-folder 21:18)
  - Pittsylvania in World War I, ca. 1918, 40 pp., 5 items. (Box-folder 21:19)
  - Poems by Duval Porter for Maud C. Clement, ca. 1928, 2 AMsS. (Box-folder 21:20)
  - Mr. Treadway's Resolution- Resolution of Pittsylvania County, 1861, n. d., TMsS, 4 pp. (Box-folder 21:21)
  - Notes on Pittsylvania County by Maud C. Clement, n. d., 26 pp. (Box-folder 21:22)
  - Pittsylvania Wills, n.d., ca. 100 pp. (Box-folder 21:23)
  - Illustrations for History of Pittsylvania County,n.d., 13 items. (Box-folder 21:24)
  - Notes on Pittsylvania County Historical Association, n.d., AMsS, 3 pp. (Box-folder 21:25)
  - Notes on Public Schools and Private Schools in Pittsylvania County by Maud C. Clement, n. d., AMsS, 18 pp. (Box-folder 21:26)
  - Rawley Martin U. D. C. Roster, 1896-1940, n. d., TMsS, 4 pp. (Box-folder 21:27)
  - Our Ancestors: The History of Families of Pittsylvania County Virginia, by Maud C. Clement, [1905?], Brochure. (Box-folder 21:28)
- Series XV: Various Books
  - Account Ledger, ca. 1924, ca. 95 pp. (Box-folder 22:1)
  - A Bible Notebook, ca. 1928-1929, ca. 188 pp. (Box-folder 22:2)
  - Diary of Maud C. Clement, 1929, 251 pp. (Box-folder 22:3)
  - Our Garden Log, ca. 1960-1964, ca. 46 pp. (Box-folder 22:4)
  - Poetry and Woodcuts, n. d., Scrapbook, 24 pp. (Box-folder 22:5)
  - Book of Bettie Pigg Carter, n. d., ca. 130 pp. (Box-folder 22:6)
  - Spencerian Handy Atlas of the World, 1903, 110 pp. (Box-folder 23:1)
  - Atlas of The War in Europe, 1915, 9 pp. (Box-folder 23:2)
  - The Literary Digest Atlas, 1922, 48 pp. (Box-folder 23:3)
  - Va. Edition- American Motorist, 1924 May, 96 pp. (Box-folder 23:4)
  - Maps of the United States, n. d., 8 items. (Box-folder 23:5)
  - Maps of Virginia, n. d., 6 items. (Box-folder 23:6)
  - Maps of Europe, n. d., 8 items. (Box-folder 23:7)
  - Maps, Foreign- Non-European, n. d., 8 items. (Box-folder 23:8)
- Series XVI: Memorabilia
  - Clippings and copies of poems by Maud C. Clement, n.d., Clippings, 25 items. (Box-folder 24:1)
  - Film negatives, Rutledge, Beffie, etc., 1923-1935 (Box-folder 24:2)
  - Rachel Jackson: An Informal Biography by Meade Minnigerode, 1925 May 16, 5 pp. (Box-folder 24:3)
  - The Hermitage, 1927 August 1, Pamphlet, 52 pp. (Box-folder 24:4)
  - Photostat of the Tribune Calendar from the Chicago Tribune, 1965 May 1 (Box-folder 24:5)
  - Clippings re: John Powell, n. d., 3 items. (Box-folder 24:6)
  - Religious Memorabilia, n. d., 12 items. (Box-folder 24:7)
  - Treasured clippings of Maud C. Clement, n. d., 36 items. (Box-folder 24:8)
  - Prayers collected by Maud C. Clement, 24:9 (Box-folder 40 items.)
  - Pictures of churches and religious subjects, n. d., 38 items. (Box-folder 24:10)
  - Notes relating to Old Beet,n. d., AMsS, 6 pp. (Box-folder 24:11)
  - Research notes of Maud C. Clement, n. d. (Box-folder 24:12)
  - Assorted magazine and newspaper clippings of Maud C. Clement, n. d., 67 items. (Box-folder 24:13)
  - Newspaper clippings re: authors and book reviews, n. d., 50 items. (Box-folder 24:14)
  - Newspaper clipping re: death of John W. Daniel, n. d. (Box-folder 24:15)
  - Reprint Chatham Tribune, 1874 August 20 re: Civil Rights, weather, economy, n. d., Newspaper clipping. (Box-folder 24:16)
  - Re: Averett College, 1959 October 18, Newspaper clippings, 3 items. (Box-folder 24:17)
  - Re: Schools in general, Clippings, 4 items. (Box-folder 24:18)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper and magazine clippings, n. d., 28 items. (Box-folder 24:19)
  - Tobacco Growing in Louisiana, 1937 August 1, Newspaper clipping. (Box-folder 24:20)
  - Memorial poem by Duval Porter on death of John W. Daniel, n. d., Clipping. (Box-folder 24:21)
  - Re: Christmas 1944, ca. 1944, Cards, clippings, 25 items. (Box-folder 25:1)
  - The Key Outpost, 1944 December 29, Newspaper, 4 pp. (Box-folder 25:2)
  - A Thought of You at Christmas, Christ Church, Martinsville, Va., 1944, Pamphlet, 6 pp. (Box-folder 25:3)
  - Treasurer's Report, Emmanuel Episcopal Church, 1946, DS. (Box-folder 25:4)
  - The Good News of The Gospel by Reverend Victor B. Stanley, 1946, TMsS, 4 pp. (Box-folder 25:5)
  - Projects Designed by Wyatt C. Hendrick, 1953 January 1, TMsS, 28 pp. (Box-folder 25:6)
  - The Names of The Streams and Mountains in Bedford County, Va. by Kenneth E. Crouch, 1959, Pamphlet, 5 pp. (Box-folder 25:7)
  - Re: Rawkey Martin Chapter, Va. Division, U. D. C., 1960-1962, 4 printed items. (Box-folder 25:8)
  - Minutes of the Sixty-Sixth Annual Convention October 3-5, 1961, U. D. C., Va. Division, Inc., 1961, Printed item, 208 pp. (Box-folder 25:9)
  - Ordination Bulletin for Church of the Epiphany, 1064 June 24, 2 items. (Box-folder 25:10)
  - Floor plan for Parish Hall of Emmanuel Episcopal Church, n. d., Printed item. (Box-folder 25:11)
  - Letterhead with stamps from Country Life, n. d., 18 items. (Box-folder 25:12)
  - Miscellaneous snapshots, n. d., 3 items. (Box-folder 25:13)
  - Historical notes and clippings, n. d., 12 items. (Box-folder 25:14)
  - An Invitation to Grand Country Frolic,August 9, TM (Box-folder 25:15)
  - Federal forms for ordering tombstones, n. d., DS, 5 items. (Box-folder 25:16)
  - Sample of English- made paper used by Virginians in 1767, n. d., 2 items. (Box-folder 25:17)
  - The Virginia School Report by R. F. Walker, Superintendent, 1875, TMs, 126 pp. (Box-folder 25:18)
  - The President's Camp on the Rapidan by Thomas Lomax Hunter, n. d., Pamphlet. (Box-folder 25:19)
  - Virginia Country Estates, n. d., 80 pp., 2 items. (Box-folder 25:20)
- Series XVIII: Scrapbooks and Maps
  - Re: Carter- Clement families and Virginia history, n.d., Scrapbook #1, ca. 50 pp.
  - Magazine clippings on silverware, n.d., Scrapbook #2, ca. 20 pp.
  - Church history and religious clippings, special emphasis on Emmanuel Episcopal Church, Chatham, n.d., Scrapbook #3, ca. 28 pp.
  - Prose clippings, 1958, n.d.
    Scrapbook #4, 26 pp.
  - 5 surveyors maps of Southwest Virginia, n.d., Oversize maps, photostats.